Guide to the Mary Butts Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers of Mary Butts, [ca.1900]-37; Series I; 6.3; (15 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - Poetry: Bound volumes and related drafts
      - "Poems 1927 (first drafts)"
        - Holograph volume, 1927-30 (Box 5, Folder 97)
          Also contains: [Automatic writing]
      - "Poems 1926-27, final versions (Typists' MS for poems 1925, 1926-1927)"
        - Holograph volume, 1925-29 (Box 5, Folder 98)
          "Advice of the Yi-King"
          "Avenue Montaigne"
          "Cassanova [sic] at Antibes"
          "Château Galliard"
          "Corfe"
          "Douananez" [sic]
          "Juan les Pins"
          "On Vexin"
          "Parenthesis"
          "Picus Martius"
          "Prayer (J.C.)"
          "Prayer (M.G.)"
          "Pythian Ode"
          "On an American Wonder-Child"
          "Rites de Passage"
          "Surprise Song"
          "The Little Party"
          "Thinking of Saints and of Petronius Arbiter"
          "Two Ways of Not Seeing the World"
          "7.8.29 (sketch)"
        - "Advice of the Yi-King," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 99)
        - "Cassanova [sic] at Antibes," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 100)
        - "Château Galliard," typescripts and typescript carbon (Box 6, Folder 101)
        - "Corfe," printed version, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 102)
        - "Douarnenez," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 103)
        - "On the American Wonder Child who translated Homer before she was ten years old," typescript (Box 6, Folder 104)
          See also: Essays, Untitled [Essays 1929], Box 13, Folder 184
        - "On Vexin," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 105)
        - "Parenthesis," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 106)
        - "Rites de Passage," printed version, Pagany, [1931] (Box 6, Folder 107)
        - "Specimen Poems for Collection," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 108)
          "Thinking of Saints"
        - "The Little Party," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 109)
        - "Two Ways of Not Seeing the World," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Poetry: Individual Poems
      - "A Consummation," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - "A Warrior Song," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 112)
      - "G.I. 2.9.14," typescript, 1914 Sep 2 (Box 6, Folder 113)
      - "Harry Pilcer at the Pavillion, Spring 1914," typescript (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - "Last Draft of Sergey Poem"
        See: Short Stories, "New MSS," Box 6, Folder 126
      - "One View of the Question S. C.," typescript, 1913-14 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      - "One Woman's Work," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 116)
      - "Return," holograph, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Short Stories: Bound volumes and related drafts
      - Untitled [Stories 1925]
        - Holograph volume, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 118)
          Contains: "Honey Get Your Gun"; "Scylla and Charybdis"
      - Untitled [Stories 1925-27]
        - Holograph volume, 1925-27 (Box 6, Folder 119)
          Contains: "The House Party"; "Scylla and Charybdis"
      - Untitled [Stories 1927-28]
        - Holograph volume, 1927-28 (Box 6, Folder 120)
          Contains: "After the Funeral," second draft; "Fumerie," second draft; "Septentrion," second draft
        - "After the Funeral," typescript, corrected, 1927 Nov (Box 6, Folder 121)
        - "After the Funeral," printed version, The London Mercury, [1932 Dec] (Box 6, Folder 122)
          See also: Essays, "Wishart Pamphlet [...]," Box 13, Folder 186
      - Untitled [Stories 1933]
        - Holograph volume, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 123)
          Contains: "Ford's Last Dancing (Parties)"; "What the Moon Saw"; "The Hermit and the Harpy Tomb"
          Also contains: Reviews, 1933; "The Art of Montague James" [essay]; Preface to Ashe of Rings
        - "The Master's Last Dancing (Parties)," second draft, holograph, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 124)
        - "What the Moon Saw: a Sennen Year" holograph draft, [1932]
          See: Novels, Death of Felicity Taverner, Box 8, Folder 149
        - "The Tomb of the Snatchers," holograph, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 125)
      - "New MSS"
        - Holograph volume, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 126)
          "The Lover" ["A Lover"]
          "Caesar and the Pirates" ["One Roman
          Speaks"]
          "The Guest"
          Also contains: "Last draft of Sergey poem" [poem]
        - "The Guest," printed version, The London Mercury (Box 7, Folder 127)
        - "A Lover," printed version, The London Mercury, 1934 Oct (Box 7, Folder 128)
        - "One Roman Speaks," printed version, The Cornhill Magazine, 1935 Jun (Box 7, Folder 129)
      - "Stories, etc. (Cornish sketches)"
        - Holograph volume, 1934-37 (Box 7, Folder 130)
          "Look Homeward Angel"
          "[On C.A. (Angus' sketch)] [II]"
          "Magic Maps" ["Mappa Mundi"]
          "A Warning"
          "On T.S.E.'s Heresy Game" [essay]
          "National Mania (protem)" [essay]
          "Siene-Fishing in the West" [essay]
        - "Mappa Mundi," typescript, corrected, [1937] (Box 7, Folder 131)
          See also: Essays, "Stories--Essays, etc.," Box 13, Folder 187
        - "The Warning," printed version, Life and Letters Today, 1935 Jan (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Short Stories: Individual Stories
      - "Altar-Lights" ["From Altar to Chimney Piece"], second draft, holograph volumes, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 133)
        See also: Novels, Death of Felicity Taverner, Box 8, Folder 149
      - "Change," typescript, corrected, [1922] (Box 7, Folder 134)
      - "Green"
        See: Novels, The Macedonian, Box 9, Folder 159
      - ["In Bayswater" or related story?], fragments, holograph and typescript (Box 7, Folder 135)
      - "Journey's End"
        See: Novels, The Macedonian, Box 9, Folder 158
      - "Madonna of the Magnificat"
        See: Poetry, "Poems: Autumn 1915, Winter 1916, Autumn 1917," Box 5, Folder 94
      - "Magic," holograph, 1920 Feb 8 (Box 7, Folder 136)
      - "A Magical Experiment," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 137)
      - "Vision," printed version, The Egoist, 1918 Sep (Box 7, Folder 138)
      - "With and Without Buttons," typescript carbon, corrected, [1932] (Box 7, Folder 139)
      - "The Unknown," holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 140)
      - Untitled, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Novels
      - Ashe of Rings, holograph preface
        See: Stories, Untitled [Stories 1933], Box 6, Folder 123
      - "Backwards from Babylon," holograph volumes, 1923 Aug 28 (Box 7, Folder 142-144)
        By MB and Cecil Maitland, with portions of manuscript in his handwriting, signed by both
      - The Death of Felicity Taverner
        - First draft, last chapters, holograph volume, [1931] (Box 7, Folder 145)
          Volume also contains: "Nearchus" and "Preface," second draft, from The Macedonian; Reviews, 1931
        - Revision, chapters I-V, holograph volume, 1930-31 (Box 8, Folder 146-147)
        - Second draft, chapters VI-XIV, holograph volume (Box 8, Folder 148)
        - Revision, chapters XV-XX, holograph volume, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 149)
          Volume also contains: "Altar-Lights" [story]; "What the Moon Saw: a Sennen Year" [story]
      - Imaginary Letters, second draft, holograph volume, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - Julian the Apostate
        - Research notes, "Notes on Julian and the IVth Century," holograph volume, 1935-[36] (Box 8, Folder 151)
        - Loose notes removed from "Notes on Julian and the IVth Century", 1936, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 152)
        - First draft, holograph volume, 1936 Sep 27 (Box 9, Folder 153)
        - Introduction, second draft, holograph volume, 1936 Oct (Box 9, Folder 154)
        - Introduction, second draft, typescript, corrected, 1936 Oct (Box 9, Folder 155)
        - "List of classical and other names occurring in enclosed MS," typescript, [19]36 Feb 2 (Box 9, Folder 156)
      - The Macedonian
        See also: Death of Felicity Taverner, Box 7, Folder 145
        - First draft, holograph volumes, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 157-158)
          Second volume also contains: "Journey's End" [story]; " The Greek Slave, Douglas Sladen" [review]
        - Second draft, holograph volumes, 1931-32 (Box 9, Folder 159-160)
          First volume also contains: "Green," second draft [story]
          Second volume also contains: Reviews, September 1932
      - Scenes from the Life of Cleopatra
        - Second draft, holograph, [1933] (Box 10, Folder 161-163)
        - Holograph pages removed from page 154, volume 1, of second draft (Box 10, Folder 164)
      - "Unborn Gods"
        - Typescript, corrected, [ca. 1916] (Box 10a, Folder 165-166)
        - Holograph corrections removed from page 15/108, Part II, Chapter IV (volume 1), n.d. (Box 10a, Folder 167)
        - Holograph correction removed from page 36, Part V, Chapter IV (volume 2), n.d. (Box 10a, Folder 168)
    - Plays
      - "Fantasia," holograph volume, [1918?] (Box 11, Folder 169)
        Contains diary entries for July 7-14, 1918, at back of volume
      - "Fantasy," holograph volumes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 170-172)
      - "A Play in Three Acts and a Prologue," holograph volumes, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 173-175)
    - Nonfiction books
      - "View of the Present State in the West"
        - Summary of "Walter's Book," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 179)
        - "View of the Present State of Western Civilisation," holograph volume, 1929 Aug (Box 12, Folder 180)
        - "View of the Present State in the West," holograph volume, 1929 Aug (Box 12, Folder 181)
    - Essays: Bound volumes and related drafts
      - "Essays: 2nd Draft", 1928
        - Holograph volume, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 182)
          "Vision and Belief"
          "Small Town"
          "The Use of the Supernatural in
          Contemporary Fiction"
      - "Ghosties and Ghoulies: Uses of the Supernatural in English Fiction," printed version, The Bookman, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 183)
      - Untitled [Essays 1929]
        - Holograph volume, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 184)
          "Aldous Huxley," first draft
          "Coda: Tony & Walter"
          Also contains: ["On an American Wonder Child" (poem)]
          - "Aldous Huxley," holograph volume, corrected, 1929 May (Box 13, Folder 185)
      - "Wishart Pamphlet, Harmsworth Pamphlet"
        - Holograph volume, 1931-32 (Box 13, Folder 186)
          ["Warning to Hikers"]
          ["Traps for Unbelievers"]
          "With and Without Buttons" [story]
          "After the Funeral" [story]
          Reviews
      - "Stories--Essays, etc., (second drafts)"
        - Holograph volume, 1936-37 (Box 13, Folder 187)
          Contains: "On Bloomsbury"
          Also contains: "Mappa Mundi" [story]
        - "Bloomsbury," typescript, corrected, 1936 June (Box 13, Folder 188)
          See also: Reviews, "Reviews, etc.," Box 14, Folder 198
    - Essays: Individual Essays
      - "The Art of Montague James", [1933]
        See: Short Stories, Untitled [Stories 1933], Box 6, Folder 123
      - "Aspects of the West Country: A Village in the West," typescript, corrected, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 189)
      - "National Mania (protem)", [1937]
        See: Short Stories, "Stories, etc. (Cornish Sketches)," Box 7, Folder 130
      - "On Modern Art"
      - "On T.S.E.'s Heresy-Game", [1937]
      - "Seine Fishing in the West," typescript carbon, corrected, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 190)
        See also: Short Stories, "Stories, etc. (Cornish Sketches)," Box 7, Folder 130
      - "Specimen Chapter of Book of Literary Criticism," typescript carbon, corrected, 1928-33 (Box 13, Folder 191)
        "The Art of Montagu James" [sic]
        "Uses of the Supernatural in English
        Fiction"
      - "Spring Storm," printed version, Manchester Guardian, 1935 Jun 11 (Box 13, Folder 192)
    - Reviews
      - Reviews written by MB
        - "Mr. Wescott's Third Book," holograph, single review, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 193)
        - Reviews, 1931
          See: Novels, Death of Felicty Taverner, Box 7, Folder 145
        - Reviews, September 1932
          See: Novels, The Macedonian, Box 9, Folder 160
        - "Reviews, Sennen, [beginning] September 1933," holograph volume (Box 14, Folder 194)
          See also: Short Stories, Untitled [Stories 1933], Box 6, Folder 123
        - "Reviews, Jan. 1934-April 1934," holograph volume (Box 14, Folder 195)
        - "Reviews, [beginning] Mid-April 1934," holograph volume, 1934-35 (Box 14, Folder 196)
        - "Reviews, Articles, etc., [beginning] March 1935," holograph volume, 1935-36 (Box 14, Folder 197)
        - "Reviews, etc. (continuation 'In Bloomsbury'), Sennen, [beginning] June 1936," holograph volume, 1936-[37] (Box 14, Folder 198)
        - Printed versions, various publications, 1931-36 (Box 15, Folder 199)
      - Reviews of MB's writings
        - "Press Cuttings, etc.," bound volume, 1922-28 (Box 15, Folder 200)
        - "Cuttings," scrapbook of clippings, 1932-35 (Box 15, Folder 201-202)
        - Loose clippings, 1932-36 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND ARTWORK
    - Photographs
      - Photograph album of Mary Butts, 1917-37 (Box 15, Folder 204)
        Includes Gabriel Atkin, Guy Allen,
        Helen Ashcroft, Margaret Ashcroft,
        Frank Baughan, MB, Anthony Butts,
        Camilla Rodker Bagg, "Bolshie"
        Burnett, David Burnett, Helen
        Burnett, Jean Cocteau, Mary
        Colville-Hyde, Odo Cross, Angus
        Davidson, Douglas Goldring, Malin
        Goldring, Peggy Guggenheim, Gladys
        Hynes, Cecil Maitland, Sergei
        Maslenikoff, Peter Morris, Paul
        Robeson, John Rodker, Joan Rodker,
        Phillis Taylor, Laurence Vail,
        Pegeen Vail, Sinbad Vail, Glenway
        Wescott, Monroe Wheeler, Angus
        Wilson, and several unidentified
        people
      - Identification key to album, by Nathalie Blondel, typescript (Box 15, Folder 205)
        This key contains some known misidentifications, which are noted on a separate list in this folder
        Accompanied by 1980s clipping, christmas card, and post-it note by CB, removed from album
    - Artwork
      - Atkin, Gabriel, "Illustrations to Wordsworth," pen and ink (Box 15, Folder 206)
      - Cocteau, Jean, portrait of Mary Butts and other subjects, 1926-29, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 207)
        Original pencil portrait of MB, in left profile with arms crossed; several pen and ink drawings, photographs and photomechanical reproductions of other drawings
      - Unknown artist: portrait of [Mary Butts?] in a striped dress, pencil and watercolor on cardboard, [ca. 1920]
        Shows subject seated in 3/4 right profile
- Family Papers, 1677-1990; Series II; 1.89; (5 boxes)
  - PAPERS OF CAMILLA RODKER BAGG
    - Correspondence
      - Family Correspondence
        - Colville-Hyde, Mary, 1930-31 (Box 16, Folder 208)
        - Briggs, Ada E., 1932 (Box 16, Folder 209)
        - Butts, Mary, 1936 Feb 5, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 210)
        - Rodker, John
          See: Papers of John Rodker, Box 19, Folder 272
      - General Correspondence
        - Adeane, Louis, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 211)
        - Bentley, G. E. (Gerald Eades), 1960 (Box 16, Folder 212)
          Accompanied by a reprint of Bentley's article, "Thomas Butts, White Collar Maecenas," PMLA Dec 1956
        - Bull, Harcourt Wesson, 1961-65 (Box 16, Folder 213)
        - Byington, Robert H., 1964-84 (Box 16, Folder 214-215)
        - Davidson, Angus, 1937-74 (Box 16, Folder 216)
        - Gathorne-Hardy, Robert, 1963 Nov 19 (Box 16, Folder 217)
        - Ingram, Herbert Frank
          See: Series III, Herbert Frank Ingram, Box 21, Folder 313
        - Johnstone, H.F.V. (Harry), 1984 (Box 16, Folder 218)
        - Morgan, Glen E., 1963-64 (Box 16, Folder 219)
        - Pevsner, Nikolaus, Sir, 1961-65 (Box 16, Folder 220)
        - Revell, Stanley, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 221)
        - Robbins, Dorothy E., 1984 (Box 16, Folder 222)
        - Warren Murton Foster & Swan, 1938, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 223)
        - Other correspondents, 1931-89 (Box 16, Folder 224)
    - Writings
      - "A Literary Friendship," typescript, corrected, 1984-87 (Box 16, Folder 225)
      - Notes used to write "A Literary Friendship" (Box 16, Folder 226)
    - Other Papers
      - Photographs of MB's grave, 1965-85 (Box 16, Folder 227)
      - "Mary Butts: Her Writings and Her World," U. C. Davis Conference, partial transcript, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 228)
      - Notes on Curious Relations by William D'Arfey [Anthony Butts], typescript, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 229)
      - Notes on MB's volumes of poetry, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 230)
      - Brief notes regarding MB and Gabriel Atkin, holograph (Box 16, Folder 231)
      - Clippings: reviews of Troublesome People: Enemies of War, 1916-86 by Caroline Moorehead, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 232)
        Removed during processing from MB's notebook, Vol. 2, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Clipping regarding the removal of the card catalog from the Reading Room of the British Museum, 1989 Jul 15 (Box 16, Folder 233)
        Removed during processing from MB's notebook, Vol. 16a, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Clipping: review of an exhibition of Christopher Wood's paintings at Kettle's Yard Gallery, Cambridge, 1990 Apr 5 (Box 16, Folder 234)
        Removed during processing from MB's notebook, Vol. 18, pp. 67- 68 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Auction catalogs from sales of Butts family items, 1932-66 (Box 16, Folder 235)
  - PAPERS OF ADA E. BRIGGS
    - Correspondence
      - Atkin, Gabriel, 1937 Mar 16 (Box 16, Folder 236)
      - Bagg, Camilla Rodker, 1931-37, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 237-238)
      - Bagg, Camilla Rodker, 1931-37, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 239-241)
      - Butts, Mary, 1897-37 (Box 17, Folder 242-244)
      - Colville-Hyde, Mary, [1923]-38 (Box 17, Folder 245-248)
      - Davidson, Angus, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 249)
      - Maitland, Cecil, [1921 Feb 3] (Box 18, Folder 250)
      - Sandecotes School, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 251)
      - Rodker, John, 1918-37 (Box 18, Folder 252)
      - Other correspondents, 1921-38 (Box 18, Folder 253)
    - Other Papers
      - Notes and receipts concerning finances with regard to Mary Butts and Camilla Rodker, 1920-33 (Box 18, Folder 254)
      - Auction catalog for the contents of The Salterns, annotated by AEB, 1923 Jun (Box 18, Folder 255)
      - "In a Bombed House: an Elegy in Memory of Anthony Butts" by William Plomer, printed booklet, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 256)
        With "Catalogue of Some of Blake's Pictures at 'The Salterns'" tipped inside front cover, and envelope annotated by AEB regarding the sale
      - Clipping of photo of The Salterns after it burned, 1950 Jun 10 (Box 18, Folder 257)
  - PAPERS OF ANTHONY BUTTS
    - Writings
      - "Iphigenia in Argos," typescript and holograph play, and related draft of letter (Box 18, Folder 258)
      - "Dora Jordan, or, The Comic Muse," typescript play, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 259-260)
  - BUTTS FAMILY PAPERS
    - "Pedigree of the Family of Butts", ca. 1890-1930 (Box 18, Folder 261)
      Bound typescript with manuscript annotations, a Butts genealogy from 1260 to 1930
    - Leaf from a family Bible, 1830 (Box 18, Folder 262)
      Inscribed with information about Sarah and Joseph Edward Butts and their children, 1780-1821; removed during processing from the Bible of Thomas Butts, which is cataloged separately
  - PAPERS OF MARY COLVILLE-HYDE
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming
        - Bagg, Camilla Rodker, 1932 Oct 23 (Box 18, Folder 263)
        - Bacon, Hickman Beckett, Sir, 1942 Apr 6 (Box 18, Folder 264)
        - Fox, Adam, 1942 Dec 18 (Box 18, Folder 265)
        - Miller Jones, Keith, 1942 Apr 7 (Box 18, Folder 266)
      - Outgoing
        - Briggs, Sarah, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 267)
        - Butts, Anthony, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 268)
        - Warren Murton Miller & Foster, [1906] (Box 18, Folder 269)
    - Writings
      - Article about Holbein portraits of Sir William and Lady Butts, Apollo, Vol XXII, no. 127, 1935 Mar
      - "Facts concerning the Family of Sir William Butts, whose portrait by Holbein [...]", typescript, [ca. 1930-35]
        See: Papers of John Rodker, Box 19, Folder 281
    - Other Papers
      - Copy of Last Will and Testament, 1941-44 (Box 18, Folder 270)
      - News clippings and articles regarding the portrait of Sir William Butts thought to be by Holbein, 1930-[35] (Box 18, Folder 271)
        See also: Oversize, Box 23, Folder 332
  - PAPERS OF JOHN RODKER
    - Correspondence
      - Bagg, Camilla Rodker, 1929-36 (Box 19, Folder 272-274)
      - Briggs, Ada E., 1921-37 (Box 19, Folder 275-277)
      - Butts, Anthony, 1937 Mar 11 (Box 19, Folder 278)
      - Butts, Mary, 1929-36, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 279)
      - Cohen, Sonia, 1929 Jan 11 (Box 19, Folder 280)
        Photocopy of outgoing letter
      - Colville-Hyde, Mary, 1927-35 (Box 19, Folder 281)
        Accompanied by a typescript history of the supposed Holbein portrait of Sir William Butts, written by Mary Colville-Hyde; also accompained by a letter from Harry Lawrence on the same subject
      - The Garden School, 1927-29 (Box 19, Folder 282)
      - The Haven School, 1929-30 (Box 19, Folder 283)
      - Pankhurst & Barrett, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 284)
      - Perowne & Co., 1928-29 (Box 19, Folder 285)
      - Roche, Son & Neale, 1926-37 (Box 19, Folder 286)
      - St. Margaret's School, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 287)
      - Southern, Walter D., 1929 (Box 19, Folder 288)
      - Warren Murton Miller & Foster, 1928-30 (Box 19, Folder 289)
        See also: Oversize, Box 24, Folder 335
      - Vanda, Poppea, 1926-27 (Box 19, Folder 290)
      - Other correspondents, 1929-35 (Box 19, Folder 291)
    - Other Papers
      - Notes concerning Camilla Rodker, 1926-29 (Box 19, Folder 292)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND ARTWORK
    - Photographs
      - Briggs, Ada E., [1880s]-1926 (Box 20, Folder 293)
      - Briggs, Sarah, [ca. 1900] (Box 20, Folder 294)
      - Butts, Frederick John, [ca. 1940s] (Box 20, Folder 295)
        Photograph of portrait miniature painted ca. 1860
      - Butts, Mary, [ca. 1892]-1919 (Box 20, Folder 296)
        See also: Oversize, Box 24, Folder 334
      - Butts Family on the yacht "Vanity", [1890s]
        Shows MB, Mary Colville-Hyde (then Mrs. Butts), Frederick John Butts, Ada E. Briggs, and the crew of the yacht
      - Colville-Hyde, Mary, [ca. 1885]-1914 (Box 20, Folder 297)
        One photo includes MB as an infant
      - [Fisher, Kitty (d. 1767)?], [1920] (Box 20, Folder 298)
        Photograph of portrait once owned by the Briggs family, thought by them to be by Johann Zoffany, of the actress Kitty Fisher
      - The Salterns, [ca. 1900] (Box 20, Folder 299)
    - Artwork
      Briggs, Irlam
      - Portrait of Mary Butts in a green dress, watercolor on paper, [ca. 1905-10] (Box 20, Folder 300)
        Half length portrait showing left profile
      - Portrait of Mary Butts as Saint Cecilia, oil on canvas, [ca. 1905-10]
        Fragment, shows head and shoulders, left profile
- Papers of Others, 1931-86; Series III; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  - ROBERT H. BYINGTON
    - ["The Quest for Mary Butts"], typescript, [1981] (Box 21, Folder 301-310)
  - HERBERT FRANK INGRAM
    - Writings on Mary Butts
      - "Poole's Forgotten Genius," typescript carbon and printed version, Poole and Dorset Herald, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 311)
      - "Mary Butts (of Poole), 1890- 1937" (for "Dorset Worthies"), typescript, [1983] (Box 21, Folder 312)
    - Research Correspondence
      - Bagg, Camilla Rodker, 1966-84 (Box 21, Folder 313)
      - Connolly, Cyril [copy], 1969 (Box 21, Folder 314)
      - Dorset Natural History and Archaeological Society, 1965-83 (Box 21, Folder 315)
      - Johnstone, H. F. V. (Harry), 1965-83 (Box 21, Folder 316)
      - Other correspondents, 1965-72 (Box 21, Folder 317)
    - Research Files